

Benjamin Gray

(781) 696-2769 benjamingray85@gmail.com ben-gray.com github.com/ioncrash

Junior web developer, transitioning from several years in web editing and publishing, as well as teaching. Having completed an immersive training course at General Assembly, am looking for an opportunity to gain experience and expand my knowledge.

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- AJAX
- Bootstrap
- Sass
- Ember
- Node.JS
- Express API
- JavaScript
- Ruby on Rails
- SQL

WEB DEVELOPMENT

Training in full-stack development at General Assembly, working both individually and collaboratively in an immersive, intense environment

- Used Ember, Ruby on Rails, and YouTube API to create You-Riff, an app which allows users to make comments which appear at specific times on YouTube videos
- Used Google Maps API, Express API, and MongoDB to create Bucket List, an app which tracks the geographical locations of your life goals and displays them as markers on a live map.
- Used Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Grunt and Node.JS to create Pillyfish, a medication tracker which reminds you when you are running out of one of your medications
- Applied version control through Git and Github to all work, including 4 major projects and daily activities
- Worked with Trello and agile development strategies to keep group projects organized and productive
- Worked with 2 major programming languages, 2 database systems, and modern backend and frontend frameworks

EXPERIENCE

Digital Editor (Network Awesome Magazine, 2011 – 2016)

Used HTML, CSS, and a proprietary CMS to oversee the development and management of an online publication, including recruiting writers, developing voice and content, digital editing and publishing.

- Managed a team of 40+ volunteer writers, including recruitment and maintaining deadlines
- Worked closely with Creative Director and COO to determine overall direction of the publication

Teacher (English Language Center, 2011 – 2016)

Taught English Language to international students from all over the world

- Created original lessons and syllabi
- Worked on curriculum development for SAT and TOEFL classes

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Art (University of Michigan 2003 - 2007)

Master of Art, Literature (Boston College 2009 - 2011)